Hello friends, I Keshav Sharma
welcome you to my YouTube channel
Insurance Sense.  Today we are talking
about Aditya Birla's Sun Life Insurance Super Trump Plan which is a very
unique plan, an amazing plan.  We will talk
about its benefits, its
UT, we will understand it
as an example and also learn
about its riders.  My
request to you is to keep watching this video till the end.
If you like this video of mine
, please like,
subscribe and share it so that
all my upcoming videos can reach you.   First of all, let's
talk
about its benefits.  There are three types of plan options in this.  The
first is labor cover, increasing cover and the
third is labor cover with return of
premium.  The next facility inside it is
Inenz Protects Hai Against Death.  That is,
in whatever form the death occurs, whether it is a
normal death or death due to any disease
or accidental death, the
nominee will be given his entire lump sum assured
or the next facility in this is terminality.
Terminality means
that if two doctors recommend that the policy
holder will die in the next six months,
then he will be
given 50% of the sum assured.   The
next feature is Crit and
Decity. If a customer policy holder suffers
a critical death, then whatever
sum assured he has taken for the critical death, he will be
given the entire sum assured.  Next is
disability i.e. accidental, if a
policy holder gets any disability
i.e. both his hands get damaged or
permanent i.e. legs get damaged then
all his upcoming premium will be waived off.  The
next feature is that the
benefit payout option for lumpsum and monthly
income. In the absence of the policy holder, if the
nominee wishes, he can take the entire lumpsum payout
or whatever sum the
policy holder has taken, he can take it as monthly
income.  The next
feature is the facility to pay the
premium for a limited period and throw the
policy.  This means that whatever your
premium is, you can pay it on Limited Pay also.  That
means you can pay premium within 5 years, 7 years, 10 years, 15 years or
whatever policy term you have taken.   The
next feature is special
discount for salary customers or female
life.  All our corporate customers
who are employed will be
given discount on premium.  Female customers who
take this policy will be
given discount as per the male policy.
Next Facility Option to defer
premium by 12 months with cover continuing
benefit.  This means that if the policy
holder's financial
condition deteriorates in any year or an
emergency arises, he cannot make the payment that year.  If
he wants,
he can make the payment next year by calling customer care.  That
means he can delay the payment for up to 12 months.
He can collect this year's payment and next year
's payment.  For this,
your policy should continue for 5 years when
you can avail its benefits.  Next
feature inside it is Get 100% Premium
Back as Early Exit Value.  This means that
if your policy continues for 30 years.
If your age is above 60 years.
If all your liabilities have been completed.
If you want that now I do
not want to continue this policy
and all my premium should be returned.
You can exit from this policy.
The company will refund all your premiums.  The
next feature inside it
is Insta Payment and Claim.  This means that if the
policy holder dies, the nominee can
call the customer care and get
₹1 lakh for emergency help within one working day
and the remaining
payment will be
given to the nominee after the documents are complete.  The next
feature is the facility to change
premium payment.  This means that if the
premium mode you have taken is
yearly, then you
can also get it done half yearly.  You
can also get it done quarterly.  You can also do it monthly.   Apart
from monthly, you can also get it done yearly.
You can change any mode inside it.
Next facility is health living
with inbuilt inside it.  There is also a health management service.
This means that if you
want to know about your health or
if you get any disease, you can
download Aditya Birla's app and discuss your health with
them.
If the doctor recommends you in it,
you will be
given a discount on whatever tests you have to undergo and whatever medicines you have to undergo.  The next feature
within this is Increase Some Assured Will in
Life Stage Protection.  You can also get your sum assured
increased on time.  If
you have taken an individual policy.
If you are not married.  If you get married,
you can get your sum assured increased.
Even after you have children, you
can increase your sum insured under this scheme.
Next we will know about its credit.  The
entry age in this is from
18 years to 65 years under option one and two.
Option three has age entry ranging from 18 years to 55 years.
It has the age of
maturity.  The minimum maturity age is 28
years.  The maximum maturity age in this is
85 years.  In this, the premium
payment is limited, that is, within option one and two,
you can also take the option of 5 years.
You can pay premium for 7 years, 10 years, 12 years, 15 years, 20 years or up to 60 years.
And
under option three, you can take a 5 year option
, you can also take a 10 year option, you
can also take a 15 year option.  It depends on which
option you take, which premium
payment term option you take.  Next is
its policy term, the
minimum policy term in this is 5 years and the
maximum policy term in this is 55 years
and the minimum policy term in regular pay will be 10 years.
Next is the
sum assured in this, the minimum sum assured in this is Rs 25
lakh.  There
is no limit on maximum sum assured.  It depends on your
income.  In this premium payment
mode, you
can also make yearly payment within KK.  You can also make payment half yearly.  You can
make payment quarterly as well as
monthly within this.
Three types of plan options are given in this.  The
first is labor cover which includes death
benefit.  Death benefit means that
you may die due to any reason, whether it is a normal
death, an accident,
or a disease.  In that,
normally the
entire sum assured will be given in case of death.  Next
is the facility inside it, Labor Terminals.  This is provided
inbuilt.  Terminality means
that two doctors recommend it.
If the policy holder suffers from a serious illness.
What will the company do if the same doctor recommends it and he dies in the next 6 months?
50% of the sum
assured he has taken will be given to him first.  If
sum assured of Rs 1 crore is taken then Rs 50 lakh will be given.  The
remaining Rs 50 lakh will be
given after his death.  Next is
Wavier of Premium and Terminality and
Accidental Death and Total Permanent
Disability.  This means that if
terminality occurs, the
premium due will be waived off.
If any total
permanent disability occurs due to the accident.  If
both hands or legs get damaged.
If that customer is not fit to work.
All his upcoming premiums will be waived off.  These
three benefits are inbuilt in this level cover.  The
next feature in this
plan is that it has increasing cover and
death benefit which is inbuilt in it.
Terminal illness is inbuilt in it.
Web Premium and Terminality and Total
Permanent Disability are also inbuilt in it.  There
is one more facility inside it.
Whatever is assured in this, it will keep
increasing by 5% every year.   That
means, if your policy is worth Rs 1 crore, then
5% of it will keep increasing by another 5% next year.
This will go up to the next 100%.  Next, the
third plan in this is Labour Covered with Return
and Premium.  Under this, you will
also get death benefit, terminal benefit and webber
of premium.  Terminal and death benefits will
also be available and within this, you will get the right
of premium i.e. return premium.  If nothing happens to
you.  If you mean by this, if
nothing happens to our policy holder during the entire policy term, then all his premium will be
returned to him.  Now
we will understand all three plans as examples.
First we will understand about level cover.
Mr. Sharma who purchased this plan for
level cover when he was 35
years old.  The sum assured he has taken is
₹1 crore, the
policy term he takes in his premium payment is 50 years, the
lump sum death benefit he takes is ₹2200, his
annual premium will be ₹2200, when
he purchased the plan, his
age was 30, 35 years,
he has taken a policy term of 50 years, that is,
his policy is valid till his age of 85 years, he dies
in his 35th year, he
dies in the 35th year of his policy term.  The
nominee will get the full
benefit of ₹1 crore and the money will be
given to the nominee
after the death of the policy holder.  The next example is
increasing cover.  Mr. Sharma is
40 years old at that time and takes a premium payment
term of 15 years.  That means they will make the payment
only for 15 years.  The
policy term is 45 years.  Those who
take death benefit, those who take option,
they take income.  The sum
insured is ₹1 crore.  The
premium that will come will be ₹99535.  The
total payment he will make within 15 years will be Rs 14935.
When she took this policy, she was
40 years old.  The policy term he had was
45 years, which means the
policy would run till his age of 85 years.
He dies within the policy term i.e. 30 years.  So the
money that Mr. Sharma will get will be the sum
insured i.e. 5% increase.   There will be an
increase every year.
In the coming 20 years, the money that his nominee will get will be
₹ crore, that is,
his total sum assured is ₹ 1 crore. The
cover that he took is an increasing cover,
that means it will increase by 5% every year, which
after his death, his nominee will get ₹ 2
crore.  Let us understand the next example.
Labour cover with return of premium.
Mr. Sharma whose age is 45 years.  If he will pay the policy
premium term, he will take a policy term of 15 years.
He has
taken a death benefit option of 40 years. He has taken Income Plus
and Lumpsum. For the term of Rs
1 crore, he will pay a premium of
Rs 7650. The
premium he will pay for 15 years will be Rs
1464750.
When he took the policy,
his age was 45 years and he took a policy term of 40 years, that
is, his policy will run till the age of 85 years.
If he dies before the policy term,
Mr. Sharma will be
given ₹1 crore to his nominee.  If
Mr. Sharma survives during these policy terms.
If someone does
not die and survives, then whatever
premium they have
paid will be returned to them.
If Mr. Sharma dies before that,
if he
takes a sum assured of Rs. 1 crore, then Rs. 1 lakh will be given to his nominee first and
then Rs. 883 will be given to him as income for the
next 240 months.
These are the three examples. Some
riders are also given in this plan.  Riders mean
that
we can avail their facilities by paying some extra premium.  The
first rider is Extent Death and
Disability.  This means that
through external factors we develop some disability
, some hands get damaged, both legs get
damaged.  We are
not in a position to work.  So all our upcoming
premiums will be waived under this.   The
next rider is Cretans Riders, which means
we can buy Cretans riders ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 50 lakh.
If we get any
cretinism.  What will the company do if someone gets cancer
or some serious disease
?  We will be given the length of the sum assured we have taken.   It will be
given at the time of illness.  The rest of the
face rider will be closed.  Next is the
surgical care rider.  If we undergo
any
surgery for any serious disease, then
all our premiums will be
waived for that also.  Next is our Hospital
Care Rider.  Whatever amount we have taken, if we get
admitted to the hospital,
we will be given the facility for that also.
Next is the external death
benefit.  This means that
if we die through an external claim,
we will be given the same sum assured as our sum assured and extra.
If our sum assured is ₹1 crore, then
₹1 crore extra will be given
on taking the rider.  Next facility web
premium inside it.  Baby and Premature means
that if we take this rider and suffer from
any serious illness or
something happens to us, then on taking this rider,
all our premium will be waived.  If
you like this plan, if you
want this plan, then you can call me on my number
98991415.
You can mail me.
If you have any question related to this plan,
you can SMS me at sarva1373@gmail.com.
I provide service at pan India level.  Please
give me a chance to serve you once.  Hello sir